Edwin K. Wong

Alameda, CA 94501 · 415.307.8858 · edwinwongsf@gmail.com

Summary

Passionate technical thought leader focused on building amazing consumer experiences. I bring deep DevOps and infrastructure experience shipping high-impact features to billions of users. I solve problems, prototype solutions, and organize smart people to achieve peak performance.

Experience

GitHub

GitHub, Inc. - Senior Product Manager - 2/2019 - present

- Driving internal developer experience: increasing dev satisfaction NPS, scaling incident response, reducing lead time and change failure rate.
- Owned Service Catalog, management system improving incident routing velocity, traceability, and engineering standards. Near 90% engagement for technical users.
- Drove design sprints for GitHub Pages 2.0 spike focused on a full featured cloud experience.



Microsoft Corporation – Senior Program Manager - 4/2018 - 2/2019

- Product Leader on Azure DevOps redesigning and driving portfolio management tools and scalable agile framework support. Shipped and tested portfolio management tools.
- Customer obsessed research, leading to prototype OKR management tools for Azure DevOps. Beta tested with a small focus group.
- Dev Services division moved to GitHub on 2/2019



Credit Karma, Inc. – Engineering Manager - 10/2016 - 4/2019

- Hands on tech lead driving build, infrastructure, and metrics for product engineering. Created central information systems, ETLing Jenkins/CircleCI to measure and visualize engineering KPI. Led critical decisions in modernizing dev environment and planning from monolith decomposition to
- microservices architecture.
- Increased release cadence 2x for web and native applications. Identified pain points and implemented recommendations as a catalyst to improve continuous integration as a culture.
- Create a coherent set of dev tools: chrome extension, web app, and slack bot as a gateway into build/test systems, continuous deployment pipeline, org chart, and information systems. Rolled out central bug portal reporting, routing, and monitoring.

Transitioned from Technical Program Manager 12/2017



Mozilla Corporation - Senior Technical Program Manager - 2/2013 - 10/2016

- Successfully shipped and drove product requirements for Push Notifications with service workers across Desktop, Mobile, DevTools, Platform, and Partner Engineering.
- Shipped Firefox authentication, sync client and service, partner integrations, password manager, tracking protection, push services, and unified metrics pipeline.

Transitioned from Engineering Manager 2/2014

• Cloud Services/SRE Engineering Manager responsible for all Mozilla client server applications, attached services initiatives, high availability authentication and sync services, scaling toward 20 million active users.



Pixar Animation Studios - Systems Engineer - 4/2011 - 2/2013

- Designed, developed, and deployed large-scale pipeline build, convert, and render test system; executing 15,000 jobs daily on server farm. Led to production adoption of software on a monthly cycle reducing production resources in half.
- Initiated test case management system enabling test discovery and improved access to test results. Championed web based services for desktop applications to reduce code redundancy.



Adobe Systems - Automation Systems Manager - 2/2000 - 4/2011

- Initiated and designed a single solution to automate Flash Player testing on Android, iOS, WebOS, ChromeOS. Designed API and multi-tiered service oriented architecture to manage a scaling platform.
- Reduced product certification time by 40%, increased test depth by 30% in the past year. Implemented multiple systems in dev/qa process such as code coverage, API unit testing.

Transitioned from Lead Quality Engineer 2/2007

• Lead Quality Engineer contributing to four major releases of Macromedia Flash Player. Involved in scoping, spec writing, and analysis of features from prototype to release. Worked directly with developers to create application program interfaces and feature behaviors. Participated in bug review council analyzing, assigning, and prioritizing issues.

Transitioned from Senior Support Engineer - 6/2001

Education



University of Arizona 1992-1997

- BS in Education, Major: Geoscience, Minor: Physics. Mentored under Don Huffman, co-discoverer of C60 creation
- Dean's List honorable mention, 1997.

Skills

Languages: Python, Ruby, JavaScript/Node, Bash, HTML, CSS. Applications and Frameworks: Flask, Sinatra, Node.js, React Graphics: Maya, Slim, Pixar Renderman, Pixar Presto, Figma